<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-15T15:15:41+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">VISARD</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">5 Reasons You Should Use VR Training</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/10/31/5-reasons-vr-training.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Reasons You Should Use VR Training" /><published>2018-10-31T22:21:43+02:00</published><updated>2018-10-31T22:21:43+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/10/31/5-reasons-vr-training</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/10/31/5-reasons-vr-training.html">&lt;p&gt;Nobody doubts the importance of training. Before letting your employees handle and operate expensive, dangerous equipment, you want to make sure that they know their stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how do they master the machinery if they’ve never touched it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time, we’ve relied on books, videos, or even just watching another employee,
 hoping that our recruit would absorb the skills, as if by osmosis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-better-retention-and-recollection&quot;&gt;1. Better Retention and Recollection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much information do you think employees really retain after watching a video or reading an instruction manual?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone knows that experience is the best teacher. Think about the difference between becoming a great basketball player by watching it on TV as opposed to getting out on the court and practicing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VR training gives students a chance to practice with the machinery and develop personal memories that they can utilize when the time comes to use the actual equipment. In fact, most employees retain around 60% more from VR training than though from reading or listening to a presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-realistic-scenarios&quot;&gt;2. Realistic Scenarios&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, operating these machines can be stressful, especially for a newcomer. A single mistake can spell disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why having an opportunity to experience these realistic scenarios is so valuable. This type of immersive learning provides an avenue for becoming accustomed to operating heavy equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-save-time-and-money&quot;&gt;3. Save Time and Money&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using virtual reality in education and training saves your company time and money. Period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of the increased pace of learning, recruits gain competency much faster than they otherwise would. This, in turn, drastically reduces the costs of worker training and professional development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;4-little-to-no-risk&quot;&gt;4. Little to No Risk&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a little scary when a new employee, especially if they don’t have previous experience, takes the reigns for the first time at a machine that could harm your product, themselves, or other personnel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is that a lot of heavy machinery is dangerous if improperly used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virtual reality training gives us an alternative. In a controlled virtual environment, a trainee has the freedom to make mistakes. They can then learn from those mistakes without having to deal with the risks that those mistakes entail in reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;5-remote-training&quot;&gt;5. Remote Training&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final advantage of VR learning is that we can do it remotely. That means that our recruit doesn’t have to be on-site, in the same city, or even in the same country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say that you’re an American business and you want to hire an employee from Canada. Instead of bringing them to your facility, you can set them up to train from their current location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lets you know that they’ll be a good fit for the job and makes logistics much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you know what virtual reality can do for you, are you ready to take the plunge? We understand that it can be hard to get started, which is why we’re here to help. To get started with VR training for your business, contact VISARD today.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="VR Training" /><summary type="html">Nobody doubts the importance of training. Before letting your employees handle and operate expensive, dangerous equipment, you want to make sure that they know their stuff.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">VR Training is Changing the Game</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/10/10/vr-training-is-changing-the-game.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="VR Training is Changing the Game" /><published>2018-10-10T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-10-10T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/10/10/vr-training-is-changing-the-game</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/10/10/vr-training-is-changing-the-game.html">&lt;p&gt;VR training is an excellent alternative for all types of industries because it provides an immersive training experience while eliminating any risks or dangers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know that experience is the best teacher, and this is especially true about learning from our mistakes. However, in many industries, those mistakes are either too costly or too dangerous for us to take any risks when it comes to training someone.
Virtual reality training is stepping in to solve this problem. Now, an engineer can experiment with complex systems, a manufacturer can learn the ropes with new industrial solutions, or a nuclear power-plant technician can even handle a meltdown or leak—and none of this has any detrimental consequences or costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;immersive-learning&quot;&gt;Immersive Learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason that VR training is so revolutionary is that it gives us an immersive learning experience that would otherwise be too costly or impossible to visit. For instance, engineering students or new recruits at a company can get firsthand experience using sophisticated equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond these opportunities, immersive learning is a great option for corporate all sorts of training. Mistakes can be costly, especially when they happen at an operational level or involve complex systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of relying on book knowledge or taking a risk on a recruit, corporations everywhere are starting to rely on VR lessons to let their employees get their mistakes out of the way without having to worry about the negative consequences of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vr-training-removes-personal-danger&quot;&gt;VR Training Removes Personal Danger&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another significant benefit of virtual reality is that it poses no actual danger to the user but can accurately simulate dangerous situations. The military has long taken advantage of this fact by implementing VR drills for this reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This same logic applies to industry, in which one mistake can wreak havoc on the product or even on the organization’s personnel. Because of the power of these machines, a single mistake can be terrible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By implementing this new training strategy, companies never again have to trust this equipment to a complete rookie. Instead, they can get plenty of practice in a relaxed virtual environment in which there is no liability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these benefits are why so many businesses are partnering with VISARD for their VR training programs. This state-of-the-art system has all the perks that you expect from virtual reality training but is designed with business in mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why it’s twice as effective as other VR brands. Between its automated feedback and bug-fixing capabilities, it doubles the success rate among its participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also greatly reduces the costs that businesses would otherwise pay for live training and support, in addition to having hand-tracking features that make the simulated environment that much more life-like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VISARD’s Robo Assistant will be your virtual teacher, a friendly tutor who is always ready to give explanations and assistance on demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, the free-walk technology allows users to freely move throughout the training room for an even more immersive experience.
Virtual reality is one of the most exciting technologies to emerge in recent years because it’s disrupting the entire professional development industry. Find out for yourself why so many successful businesses are training their employees with VR.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="VR Training" /><summary type="html">VR training is an excellent alternative for all types of industries because it provides an immersive training experience while eliminating any risks or dangers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Use Interactive Content to Generate Tons of Leads</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/10/10/how-to-use-iInteractive-content.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Use Interactive Content to Generate Tons of Leads" /><published>2018-10-10T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-10-10T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/10/10/how-to-use-iInteractive-content</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/10/10/how-to-use-iInteractive-content.html">&lt;p&gt;We’ve all seen it: the same boring web page. Maybe there’s some pictures and a wordy description.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of telling your customers about your product, why don’t you show it to them? 
Well, by using interactive 3D content that employs cutting-edge VR technology, you can do just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We get it. It’s especially hard to generate leads in the engineering and industrial manufacturing business. The sales process is long and complicated, involves many parties, can take over a year to sell a single machine, and it might all fall apart at the last minute anyway. 
If only there was a way to sidestep this tiresome process and instead work with legit leads…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web3d-showrooms&quot;&gt;Web3D Showrooms&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a customer arrives on the landing page of your website, what’s the first thing that they see? Or, better yet, what do they experience?
Instead of overloading them with blocks of complex text, try embedding an interactive 3D presentation on your page. Of course, you will need those detailed explanations at some point, but you want to put your best foot forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, experience is the best teacher and it also creates the most vivid memories. Web3D puts the machine right in front of the prospective buyer. It let’s them observe it from every angle, activate its various functions, look at what’s going on inside, or even take it apart. 
You can even design your 3D visualization to act like a game. Make different objectives for the user to complete to give them a tour of all the presented features and to give them a lead-generating satisfied feeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;seal-the-deal&quot;&gt;Seal the Deal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great tactic for generating leads is to offer a sample or partial demo and then require the user to provide their contact information in order to access the full experience. That way you can easily follow up with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your Web3D showroom should be a part of your overarching marketing strategy on your web page. Don’t forget to provide unique selling points (USPs), trust elements like testimonials, and a Call to Action (CTA) button that they can use to get in touch with you. Or, just use a complete Web3D presentation solution by VISARD that includes everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VISARD’s advanced VR technology is the perfect place to start if you’re ready to get to work on your very own 3D presentation. Our virtual systems can create a beautiful and engaging interactive 3D presentation that can be combined with real-time sales assistance through video chat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 21st century, more and more business is heading to the digital sphere. Don’t get left behind—take advantage of the best lead generating tool that is changing the game for industrial sales and marketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re curious about Web3D showrooms and are ready for the most advanced lead generating strategy that industrial engineering companies across the world are picking up, please feel free to reach out to us. And don’t forget to stay connected and keep your eye out for even more articles on B2B marketing for heavy engineering companies.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Web3d" /><summary type="html">We’ve all seen it: the same boring web page. Maybe there’s some pictures and a wordy description.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Virtual Trade show: Science-Fiction or near future?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/09/11/virtual-trade-show.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Virtual Trade show: Science-Fiction or near future?" /><published>2018-09-11T00:00:00+03:00</published><updated>2018-09-11T00:00:00+03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/09/11/virtual-trade-show</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/09/11/virtual-trade-show.html">&lt;p&gt;This article tackles and compares usual trade fairs with Virtual Reality trade fairs. Involved people know the workings of  trade shows, their  advantages and disadvantages . Their have been some attempts to run virtual trades hows complementary to physical trade shows.  How does the future of trade shows look like? Could the virtual show  even replace the physical one  or is this Science-Fiction?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading manufacturing companies already apply VR showrooms these days to present their machines, simultaneously saving costs and gaining new leads. But this is an expensive investment and has been reserved to leadings companies only, hasn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction-virtual-trade-fairs&quot;&gt;Introduction Virtual trade fairs:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Showcasing your machine in Virtual Reality means that you need VR glasses (like HTC Vive, Occulus or GearVR), an application where your machine(s) is shown in 3D space and maybe some additional equipment like controller and sensors depending on the appliance and needs.
Having this set-up everyone can take a look at your machine everywhere in VR.
One set of such kind of equipment may cost between $500 and $1500 excluding the development of the application, so the equipment can be obtained for an affordable price. 
Why Virtual trade shows have been reserved for leading companies have two major reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-application-costs&quot;&gt;1. Application Costs:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developing such an application can easily reach 6 figure sum or even much higher depending on the complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-lack-of-knowledge-about-virtual-reality&quot;&gt;2. Lack of knowledge about Virtual Reality:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtual Reality is a very fast expanding and new industry which finds new appliance daily. In addition, not many people have tried VR applications at all or haven’t experienced applications for the industry. This makes it hard for people to see the benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article will treat both issues, but first why even use VR solutions and why are they even so interesting for leading companies?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;comparing-usual-trade-shows-and-virtual-trade-shows&quot;&gt;Comparing usual trade shows and Virtual trade shows:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s do the math to understand one point why Virtual trade fairs are saving money for companies in first place. To do that we take an example of a company showcasing 3 machines on trade fairs and compare it to a VR solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/posts/virtual-trade-show/scheme.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; title=&quot;COMPARING USUAL TRADE SHOWS AND VIRTUAL TRADE SHOWS&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see that with a VR solution this company saves 406.000 EUR every trade fair over 10 years and the investment for a VR solution is already covered in the first trade show. Also, if meanwhile the machines need to be taken out of the daily production line, additional financial losses occur, which are omitted with the VR solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;benefits-of-vr&quot;&gt;Benefits of VR:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beside hugh savings, does the VR solution bring other advantages? The answer is simply yes! and even a lot of them. Here are some main Key Points:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;showcasing-machines-which-are-not-yet-developed&quot;&gt;Showcasing machines which are not yet developed&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Presenting clients your machine which is still in the developing process and collecting already orders.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;no-limitation-by-space&quot;&gt;No limitation by space&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In VR you have all the space you need without any limitations to the booth size.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;providing-a-guided-tour-through-your-machine&quot;&gt;Providing a guided tour through your machine&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A guided tour means that the user can just lean back and take a scripted tour about your machine, highlighting the most important features and point out benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;hidden-processes-can-be-revealed-within-the-working-machine&quot;&gt;Hidden processes can be revealed within the working machine&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;An important feature of VR is that you can show everything you imagine, for example make the covers of you machine transparent and show hidden processes while the machine is working.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;quick-exchange-to-show-variations-of-your-machine&quot;&gt;Quick exchange to show variations of your machine&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If there are different variation or customizable machine parts, you can exchange them with one “klick”.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;the-vr-technology-naturally-attracts-more-visitors-what-has-an-positive-impact-for-new-leads&quot;&gt;The VR technology naturally attracts more visitors, what has an positive impact for new leads&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Companies with a Virtual trade show have noticed a 30% raise of potential clients&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;the-vr-technology-supports-the-impression-of-an-innovative-company&quot;&gt;The VR technology supports the impression of an innovative company&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As VR is a new and innovative technology this impression will reflect on your company.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;you-can-use-the-vr-solution-as-well-for-other-purposes-and-not-only-on-trade-fairs&quot;&gt;You can use the VR solution as well for other purposes and not only on trade fairs&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For example to showcase many different machines to clients anywhere, anytime. Or as a stand alone  marketing tool in addition to usual prospects and graphics.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;flexibility&quot;&gt;Flexibility&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Transporting a big machine always includes a lot of planning and skilled employees limiting your flexibility. This is omitted with the VR solution as you only need one person with a case flying to clients in any moment. Just make an appointment and you are ready to go.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;are-there-any-obstacles-with-virtual-trade-shows-and-can-they-be-solved&quot;&gt;Are there any obstacles with Virtual Trade Shows and can they be solved?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short answer is yes, but the list is also very short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;you-can-not-touch-the-real-machine&quot;&gt;You can not touch the real machine&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As we are all humans, we like to touch things, feel them, smell them. Unfortunately this is not possible in VR (not yet developed to a high standard). This issue is almost completely overcome by taking one or a few machines to the trade fairs and a lot more in VR. This way the visitors can link the real machines to your machines in VR. Also, with today’s standards the VR is so immersive, that people forget quickly that they are in a virtual world and start acting like in the real world after one or a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;people-without-knowledge-of-modern-technology-might-have-trouble-getting-used-to-vr&quot;&gt;People without knowledge of modern technology might have trouble getting used to VR&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Some people which didn’t get in touch with modern technology, need a few more minutes to get used to VR. To shorten the learning process, an intuitive tutorial is created which gives a fast entrain. On the other hand it was noticed that a lot of non-technical peoples are even more attracted to try a new technology and have a greater experience in the end. The highest reported amount of getting used to an application is about 5 min. Usually it takes less than 1 minute.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h4 id=&quot;motion-sickness&quot;&gt;Motion sickness&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;1,5 % of people report motion sickness while trying VR for the first time. Sounds worse than it actually is. The motion sickness is a slightly dizzy state which occurs usually within 5-20 min. People start feeling a little uncomfortable and take of the VR glasses. Many VR reality solutions do not exceed this timeframe, so the motion sickness doesn’t even start in most cases and lowers the small percentage to almost non existing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the benefits of a VR solution are clearly more decisive than the downsides which are minor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;so-what-is-actually-still-stopping-companies-to-use-virtual-reality&quot;&gt;So what is actually still stopping companies to use Virtual Reality?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the point where Visards innovative business model comes into play, as this is exactly what Visards team leaders were asking themselves in 2014 when founding the company. 
Here we come back to the two questions from the top of the article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-application-costs-and&quot;&gt;1. Application Costs and&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-lack-of-knowledge-about-virtual-reality-1&quot;&gt;2. Lack of knowledge about Virtual Reality.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, let’s get to the second point, lack of knowledge about VR. 
Of course, if someone has never tried on VR glasses, it is not possible to understand the greatness and possibilities of the technology, most people don’t even think of VR as a marketing solution for the industry and are too much used to usual marketing methods. This is a reason why many people don’t even think of using VR solutions for their company - “a technology far away from imagination”. Even a search engine result doesn’t reveal a lot of industrial usage for VR applications yet. The way to overcome this is quite easy, just contact Visard, share your interests, discuss your thoughts and we will provide the possibility to make your first VR experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still one point left, the development costs. This was holding back middle sized companies to get a VR solution for themself. At first, while ordering a VR solution, you are not sure if this application will have the desired effect, in addition you have to invest quite an amount of funds (easily into 6 figures). Visard’s answer is a subscription model. You pay a little amount (starting from only 260 EUR/month) and you are ready to go. In addition you get support and updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall a Virtual trade show has only advantages and there are no doubts that in future more and more companies will present their machines in Virtual trade shows. It is also very possible that in future whole trade fairs will take place in VR. 
As this technology is just developing and the industry is experiencing the benefits of VR, your company can now be one of the first using VR solutions thanks to the business model of Visard.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="VR" /><category term="longread" /><summary type="html">This article tackles and compares usual trade fairs with Virtual Reality trade fairs. Involved people know the workings of trade shows, their advantages and disadvantages . Their have been some attempts to run virtual trades hows complementary to physical trade shows. How does the future of trade shows look like? Could the virtual show even replace the physical one or is this Science-Fiction?</summary></entry></feed>